Guide to the Brent Kramer Files on Communications Workers of America, Local 1101 WAG.344
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Brent Kramer Files on Communications Workers of America, Local 1101
1970-1991
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Kramer, Brent
WAG.344
1.25 Linear Feet in 1 record carton, and 1 half manuscript box.
Brent Kramer was an employee of the New York Telephone Company and member of the Communications Workers of America (CWA), Local 1101. This collection contains records of Brent Kramer and several of his colleagues' rank-and-file activities in Communications Workers of America Local 1101 from 1970 to the 1990s. CWA Local 1101 represented Bell System (and later Verizon) technical workers in Manhattan and the Bronx. The materials cover the strikes of 1971 and 1989, the Newman v. Local 1101, Communications Workers of America lawsuit, and Local 1101 elections.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains records of Brent Kramer and several of his colleagues' rank-and-file activities in Communications Workers of America (CWA), Local 1101 from 1970 to the 1990s. CWA Local 1101 represented Bell System (and later Verizon) technical workers in Manhattan and the Bronx.
Materials include various union publications such as newspapers, newsletters, flyers, leaflets, pamphlets, and circulars. Some publications include Ring Down, New York Generator, Final Warning, Against the Grain, The Bell Wringer, and Labor Notes. Also included are correspondence, notes, article drafts, layouts, sample ballots, legal files related to Newman v. Local 1101, Communications Workers of America (a case in which he was also a plaintiff), mailers, a Teamsters for a Democratic Union (TDU) conference program, newspaper clippings, nomination petitions, and a sign from the 1989 NYNEX strike.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Brent Kramer, October 2017. The accession number associated with this gift is 2019.004.
Biographical Note
Brent Kramer was an employee of the New York Telephone Company and member of the Communications Workers of America (CWA), Local 1101.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Dave Newman Files on the Communications Workers of America, Local 1101 (WAG 278)
Circulars (fliers); Clippings (information artifacts); Legal documents.; Newsletters.; Pamphlets.; Correspondence.; Labor unions -- Telecommunication -- United States.; Telecommunication -- Employees -- Labor unions.; Strikes and lockouts -- Telecommunication.; Labor unions -- Elections -- United States.; Strikes and lockouts -- Telephone companies -- New York (State) -- New York.; Kramer, Brent; Communications Workers of America. Local 1101 (New York, N.Y.); Communications Workers of America; Newman, David
- 7 Month Strike, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Post-Strike Union Activities, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- New American Movement (NAM) Labor Conferences and Miscellaneous Rank and File Publications, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Various Rank and File Groups in CWA 1101, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Kramer vs. Business Agent McQueeney, 1973-1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Telephone Workers' Legal Defense Committee (TWLDC) - Legal Papers and Further Publicity and Correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "Free Speech" Struggle in CWA Local 1101, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- TWLDC Funds, Endorsements and Appeal Responses, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- More Rank and File Activity in Local 1101 and Elsewhere, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Bell Wringer, 1979-1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Labor Notes Newsletter, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Labor Notes Newsletter, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Bell Wringer and Union Elections, 1983-1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Bell Wringer, Election in CWA 1101, and Rank and File Activity, 1987-1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- 1989 Strike, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Stewards' Training Packet, CWA 1101, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Local 1101 Elections, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)